Thank you so much everyone from TED, and Chris and Amy in particular.
شكراً جزيلاً لكل شخص في تيد، وكريس وآمي خاصةً.
I cannot believe I'm here.
لا أستطيع تصديق أنني هنا.
I have not slept in weeks.
لم أنم طوال أسابيع.
Neil and I were sitting there comparing how little we've slept
نيل وأنا كنا نجلس ونرى كم هو نومنا قليل
in anticipation for this. I've never been so nervous --
توقعاً لهذا. لم أكن متوتر بشدة أبداً
and I do this when I'm nervous, I just realized. (Laughter)
وأنا أفعل هذا وأنا متوتر، لقد أدركت ذلك الآن.
So, I'm going to talk about sort of what we did at this organization
إذاً، سأتحدث عمّا فعلناه في هذه المنظمة
called 826 Valencia, and then I'm going to talk
التي تسمى 826 فالنسيا، وبعد ذلك سأتحدث
about how we all might join in and do similar things.
حول كيف يمكننا جميعاً المشاركة وفعل أشياء مشابهة.
Back in about 2000, I was living in Brooklyn,
سابقاً حوالي عام 2000، كنت أعيش في بروكلين
I was trying to finish my first book,
كنت أحاول إنهاء كتابي الاول
I was wandering around dazed every day
كنت أتجول وحالة الذهول تنتابني كل يوم
because I wrote from 12 a.m. to 5 a.m.
لأنني كتبت من الساعة 12 منتصف الليل وحتى الخامسة صباحاً
So I would walk around in a daze during the day.
لذا كنت أتجول وأنا مصاب بالدوار خلال اليوم.
I had no mental acuity to speak of during the day, but I had flexible hours.
لم يكن لدي القوة العقلية لأتحدث خلال اليوم، لكن ساعات العمل كانت مرنة.
In the Brooklyn neighborhood that I lived in, Park Slope,
في الحي الذي سكنته في بروكلين، بارك سلوب،
there are a lot of writers --
هناك الكثير من الكُتاب
it's like a very high per capita ratio
أنها نسبة سكانية عالية
of writers to normal people.
من الكتاب الى الناس العاديين.
Meanwhile, I had grown up around a lot of teachers.
في هذه الأثناء، لقد ترعرت وسط الكثير من المعلمين.
My mom was a teacher, my sister became a teacher
والدتي كانت معلمة، أختي أصبحت معلمة
and after college so many of my friends went into teaching.
وبعد الجامعة العديد من أصدقائي دخلوا مجال التدريس.
And so I was always hearing them talk about their lives
ولذا كنت دائماً أسمعهم يتحدثون عن حياتهم
and how inspiring they were,
وكيف كانوا مُلهمين،
and they were really sort of the most hard-working
وأنهم حقاً أكثر من يعملون بجد
and constantly inspiring people I knew.
ودائماً ما يقومون بإلهام الناس الذين أعرفهم.
But I knew so many of the things they were up against,
لكني عرفت العديد من الأشياء التي كانت ضدهم،
so many of the struggles they were dealing with.
لذا فالكثير من المعاناة التي كانت توجههم
And one of them was that so many of my friends
وأحدها كانت أن الكثير من أصدقائي
that were teaching in city schools were having trouble
الذين كانوا يدرّسون في مدارس المدينة كانت تواجههم مشاكل
with their students keeping up at grade level,
مع تلاميذهم في الحفاظ على درجاتهم،
in their reading and writing in particular.
في القراءة والكتابة تحديداً.
Now, so many of these students had come from households
الآن، الكثير من أؤلئك التلاميذ جاءوا من أسر
where English isn't spoken in the home,
لا تتحدث اللغة الإنجليزية في بيوتهم،
where a lot of them have different special needs,
حيث لدى الكثيرون منهم إحتياجات خاصة مختلفة
learning disabilities. And of course they're working in schools
معوقات تعلم. وبالطبع هم يعملون في المدارس
which sometimes and very often are under-funded.
التي في كثير من الأحيان تعاني من قلة التمويل.
And so they would talk to me about this and say,
ولذا فأنهم يتحدثون حول هذا ويقولون
"You know, what we really need is just more people,
"تعرف، ما نحتاجه فقط هو المزيد من الناس،
more bodies, more one-on-one attention,
مزيد من الأجساد، المزيد من إنتباه شخص- لشخص آخر
more hours, more expertise from people
المزيد من الساعات، خبرة أكثر من الناس
that have skills in English and can work with these students one-on-one."
الذين لديهم مهارات في اللغة الإنجليزية وبمستطاعهم العمل مع أؤلئك التلاميذ واحد-لواحد."
Now, I would say, "Well, why don't you just work with them one-on-one?"
الآن، أقول، " حسناً، لماذا لا تعملون معهم واحد-لواحد؟"
And they would say, "Well, we have five classes of 30 to 40 students each.
فيقولون: لدينا خمسة صفوف كل منها 30 الى 40 تلميذاً.
This can lead up to 150, 180, 200 students a day.
هذا قد يقود ل 150، 180، 200 تلميذ يومياً.
How can we possibly give each student
كيف يمكننا إعطاء كل تلميذ
even one hour a week of one-on-one attention?"
إنتباه حتى ساعة واحدة أسبوعياً؟"
You'd have to greatly multiply the workweek and clone the teachers.
يتوجب عليه ضرب ساعات العمل الأسبوعية وإستنساخ المعلمين.
And so we started talking about this.
ولذا بدأنا في الحديث حول هذا
And at the same time,
وفي نفس الوقت،
I thought about this massive group of people I knew:
فكّرت في مجموعة هائلة من الناس الذين أعرفهم:
writers, editors, journalists, graduate students,
كتّاب، محررين، صحفيين، دراسات عليا،
assistant professors, you name it.
أساتذة جامعيين، الى آخره من الاشخاص
All these people that had sort of flexible daily hours
لدى كل أؤلئك الناس نوع من ساعات العمل المرنة
and an interest in the English word --
وإهتمام بالكلمة الإنجليزية--
I hope to have an interest in the English language,
أتمنى أن يكون لدي إهتمام باللغة الإنجليزية،
but I'm not speaking it well right now. (Laughter)
لكني لا أتحدثها جيداً الآن.
I'm trying. That clock has got me.
انني أحاول, ان الوقت يمضي
But everyone that I knew had an interest in the primacy of the written word
لكن أي شخص عرفته كان لديه إهتمام بأولوية الكلمة المكتوبة
in terms of nurturing a democracy, nurturing an enlightened life.
من ناحية تغذية الديموقراطية، ورعاية حياة مستنيرة.
And so they had, you know, their time
ولذا كان لديهم، كما تعلمون، وقتهم
and their interest, but at the same time
وإهتماماتهم، لكن في نفس الوقت
there wasn't a conduit that I knew of in my community
لم يكن هناك طريق عرفته في مجتمعي
to bring these two communities together.
لجلب تلك المجتمعات سوياً.
So when I moved back to San Francisco, we rented this building.
لذا عندما أنتقلت مجدداً الى سان فرانسيسكو، قمنا بإستئجار هذا المبنى.
And the idea was to put McSweeney's --
والفكرة كانت وضع ماك سويني--
McSweeney's Quarterly, that we published twice or three times a year,
مجلة ماك سويني التي نشرناها مرتين أو ثلاثة مرات سنوياً،
and a few other magazines --
وبعض المجلات الأخرى
we were going to move it into an office for the first time.
كنا سنقوم بنقلها الى مكتب لأول مرة.
It used to be in my kitchen in Brooklyn.
لقد كانت قابعة في مطبخ منزلي في بروكلين.
We were going to move it into an office,
كنا سننقلها الى مكتب،
and we were going to actually share space with a tutoring center.
وقد كنا في الواقع سنتشارك مساحة مع مركز التدريس.
So we thought, "We'll have all these writers and editors and everybody --
لذا فقد فكرنا، " سنحصل على كل هؤلاء الكتاب والمحررين وكل شخص --
sort of a writing community -- coming into the office every day anyway,
نوع من مجتمع الكتاب يأتي الى مكتب كل يوم على اي حال،
why don't we just open up
لم لا نفتحه
the front of the building for students to come in there after school,
الواجهة الأمامية للمبنى ليأتوا هناك بعد المدرسة
get extra help on their written homework,
للحصول على مزيد من المساعدة في واجباتهم المدرسية
so you have basically no border between these two communities?"
بحيث تختفي الحواجز بين هذين المجتمعين؟
So the idea was that we would be
إذاً كانت الفكرة لتكون
working on whatever we're working on,
ناجحة على أي شئ نعمل عليه
at 2:30 p.m. the students flow in and you put down what you're doing,
في الساعة 2:30 سيأتي التلاميذ وتضع أنت ما بين يديك
or you trade, or you work a little bit later or whatever it is.
أو العمل التجاري أو تعمل عليه لاحقاً
You give those hours in the afternoon
فإنك تقدم هذه الساعات بعد الظهر
to the students in the neighborhood.
الى التلاميذ في الحي.
So, we had this place, we rented it,
إذاً حصلنا على المكان وإستأجرناه
the landlord was all for it. We did this mural,
صاحب الأرض قدمها لنا وهناك كان هذا الجدار
that's a Chris Ware mural, that basically explains the entire history
ذلك جدار كريس واير، وذلك في الاساس يشرح كل تاريخ
of the printed word, in mural form -- it takes a long time
الكلمة المطبوعة على شكل جدار -- تستغرق زمنا طويلا
to digest and you have to stand in the middle of the road.
لتهُضم وينبغي عليك الوقوف في منتصف الطريق.
So we rented this space.
ً لقد إستأجرنا هذه المساحة.
And everything was great except the landlord said,
وكان كل شئ عظيما بإستثناء أن مالك الأرض قال،
"Well, the space is zoned for retail; you have to come up with something.
"حسناً، جزء من الأرض محجوز للتجزئة. يجب أن تتوصلوا لحل ما."
You've gotta sell something.
عليكم أن تبيعوا شئ ما
You can't just have a tutoring center."
لا يمكنكم الحصول على مركز تدريس فقط."
So we thought, "Ha ha! Really!"
لذا فقد فكرنا، " ها ها حقاً!
And we couldn't think of anything necessarily to sell,
ولم نستطع التفكير في أي شئ لبيعه
but we did all the necessary research.
لكننا قمنا بكل البحوث اللازمة
It used to be a weight room, so there were rubber floors below,
لقد كانت غرفة ممتلئة، فقد كانت هناك أرضية مطاطية
acoustic tile ceilings and fluorescent lights.
سقوف القرميد الصوتية، ومصابيح الفلورسنت.
We took all that down, and we found beautiful wooden floors,
تخلصنا من كل ذلك، ووضعنا أرضيات خشبية جميلة
whitewashed beams and it had the look --
حزم بيضاء
while we were renovating this place, somebody said,
بينما كنا نرمم هذا المكان قال أحدهم
"You know, it really kind of looks like the hull of a ship."
"تعرفون، إنها حقاً تبدو كجزء من جسم السفينة."
And we looked around and somebody else said,
ونظرنا في الجوار وقال شخص آخر،
"Well, you should sell supplies to the working buccaneer." (Laughter)
"حسناً، ينبغي عليك بيع اللوازم الى العامل بالقرصنة"
And so this is what we did. So it made everybody laugh,
وكان هذا ما فعلناه. لذا فقد جعلت الجميع يضحك
and we said, "There's a point to that.
وقلنا هناك فكرة من ذلك
Let's sell pirate supplies." This is the pirate supply store.
لنبيع لوازم القرصنة. " هذا متجر لبيع مستلزمات القرصنة.
You see, this is sort of a sketch I did on a napkin.
ترون، هذا نوع من المخططات التي رسمتها على منديل
A great carpenter built all this stuff and you see,
قام نجار عظيم ببناء كل هذه الأشياء
we made it look sort of pirate supply-like.
لقد جعلناها تبدو كمزود مستلزمات القرصنة
Here you see planks sold by the foot
ترون هنا ألواح مباعة بواسطة القدم
and we have supplies to combat scurvy.
ولدينا مستلزمات لمكافحة داء الاسقربوط.
We have the peg legs there, that are all handmade and fitted to you.
ولدينا أرجل الخنازير هناك، وكل هذا مصنوع يدوياً ومناسبة
Up at the top, you see the eyepatch display,
وهناك للأعلى ترون الرقعة التي تلبس على العين
which is the black column there for everyday use
الذي هو عمود فارغ هناك للإستخدام اليومي،
for your eyepatch, and then you have the pastel
رقعة العين ثم لديك ألوان الباستيل
and other colors for stepping out at night --
وألوان أخرى للخروج في الليل --
special occasions, bar mitzvahs and whatever.
المناسبات الخاصة، شريط ميتزفاهس وأي شئ.
So we opened this place. And this is a vat
إذاً فقد فتحنا هذا المكان. وهذا برميل
that we fill with treasures that students dig in.
الذي سيملىء بالكنوز التي سيبحث عنها التلاميذ
This is replacement eyes in case you lose one.
هذه عيون إضافية في حالة فقدت واحدة.
These are some signs that we have all over the place:
هذه بعض العلامات التي لدينا في كل المكان:
"Practical Joking with Pirates."
"الهزل العملي مع القراصنة."
While you're reading the sign, we pull a rope behind the counter
بينما تقرأ هذه العلامة، نسحب الحبل خلف العداد
and eight mop heads drop on your head.
وثمانية رؤوس ممسحة تقع على رأسك.
That was just my one thing -- I said we had to have something that drops on people's heads.
كان ذلك أحد الأشياء فقط -- قلت أنه ينبغي أن يكون لدينا شئ يقع على رؤوس الناس.
It became mop heads. And this is the fish theater,
وهي رؤوس مماسح. وهذا مسرح السمك،
which is just a saltwater tank with three seats,
الذي هو تنك ماء مالح فقط بثلاثة مقاعد
and then right behind it we set up this space,
ثم على الخلف تماماً نثبت هذه المساحة.
which was the tutoring center.
والتي هي مركز التدريس
So right there is the tutoring center,
إذاً هناك بالضبط يقع مركز التدريس
and then behind the curtain were the McSweeney's offices,
ثم خلف ذلك مكاتب ماك سويني
where all of us would be working on the magazine and book editing and things like that.
جميعنا سيعمل على مجلة وتحرير الكتب ومثل ذلك
The kids would come in --
سيدخل الأطفال
or we thought they would come in. I should back up.
أو أعتقدنا أنهم سيدخلوا. يجب أن أتراجع
We set the place up, we opened up, we spent months and months
جهزنا المكان، أفتتحناه، قضينا شهور وشهور
renovating this place.
نرمم المكان.
We had tables, chairs, computers, everything.
لدينا طاولات، كراسي، كمبيوترات، كل شئ.
I went to a dot-com auction at a Holiday Inn in Palo Alto
ذهبت الى مزاد على الإنترنت في فندق هوليداي إن في بالو ألتو
and I bought 11 G4s with a stroke of a paddle.
وأشتريت 11 كمبيوتر G4 مع مضارب مجاديف.
Anyway, we bought 'em, we set everything up and then we waited.
أشتريناهم، جهزنا كل شئ وبعد ذلك أنتظرنا
It was started with about 12 of my friends,
لقد بدأت مع حوالي 12 من أصدقائي،
people that I had known for years that were writers in the neighborhood.
أناس عرفتهم لسنوات وكنا كُتاب في الحي
And we sat. And at 2:30 p.m. we put a sandwich board out on the front sidewalk
جلسنا وفي الساعة 2:30 وضعنا لوحة على الرصيف في الخارج
and it just said, "Free Tutoring for Your English-Related
مكتوب عليها، " تدريس مجاني لما يتعلق اللغة الإنجليزية "
and Writing-Related Needs -- Just Come In, It's All Free."
والإحتياجات المتعلقة بالكتابة -- فقط تعالوا، كل شئ مجاني."
And we thought, "Oh, they're going to storm the gates,
ولقد أعتقدنا، " أوه، سيقومون بعصف البوابات،
they're gonna love it." And they didn't.
سيحبونها." ولم يحصل ذلك.
And so we waited, we sat at the tables, we waited and waited.
ولذا فقد أنتظرنا، جلسنا على الطاولات، وأنتظرنا.
And everybody was becoming very discouraged
أصيب الجميع بخيبة الأمل
because it was weeks and weeks that we waited, really, where nobody came in.
لأنها كانت أسابيع وأسابيع ونحن ننتظر، حيث لم يحضر أحد
And then somebody alerted us to the fact
ثم نبهنا شخص ما الى حقيقة
that maybe there was a trust gap,
أنه ربما هناك فجوة في الثقة
because we were operating behind a pirate supply store. (Laughter)
لأننا كنا نعمل خلف متجر مستلزمات القرصنة
We never put it together, you know?
لم نضع كل ذلك معاً، تعرفون؟
And so then, around that time, I persuaded a woman named Nineveh Caligari,
وعليه، قرابة ذلك الوقت، أقنعت إمرأة تسمى نينفه كاليغاري،
a longtime San Francisco educator --
معلمة قديمة في سان فرانسيسكو
she was teaching in Mexico City,
كانت تُدرّس في مدينة مكسيكو
she had all the experience necessary,
لديها كل الخبرة اللازمة
knew everything about education,
تعرف كل شئ حول التعليم
was connected with all the teachers and community members in the neighborhood --
وكانت على تواصل مع كل مجتمع المعلمين وأعضاء المجتمع في الحي.
I convinced her to move up from Mexico City where she was teaching.
أقنعتها بالإنتقال من مدينة مكسيكو حيث كانت تُدرّس
She took over as executive director.
وأخذت دور المدير التنفيذي.
Immediately, she made the inroads with the teachers
في الحال، قامت بالتواصل مع المعلمين
and the parents and the students and everything,
والآباء والتلاميذ وكل شئ،
and so suddenly it was actually full every day.
فجأة أصبح المكان ممتلئ كل يوم
And what we were trying to offer every day
وما كنا نحاول تقديمه كل يوم
was one-on-one attention.
كان إنتباه شخص لشخص
The goal was to have a one-to-one ratio with every one of these students.
كان الهدف هو الحصول على نسبة شخص لشخص مع كل من هؤلاء التلاميذ.
You know, it's been proven
تعرفون، لقد تم إثبات الأمر
that 35 to 40 hours a year with one-on-one attention,
بأن 35 الى 40 ساعة سنوياً بإنتباه شخص لشخص،
a student can get one grade level higher.
يستطيع التلميذ الحصول على مستوى أعلى.
And so most of these students, English is not spoken in the home.
ولذا فمعظم هؤلاء التلاميذ، لا يتحدثون الإنجليزية في بيوتهم.
They come there, many times their parents --
لقد جاء الكثير من أهالي الأطفال
you can't see it, but there's a church pew
لا يمكنكم رؤيتها، لكن هناك مقاعد الكنيسة
that I bought in a Berkeley auction right there --
التي أشتريتها من مزاد بيركلي هناك --
the parents will sometimes watch while their kids are being tutored.
يراقب الآباء بعض الأحيان أثناء تدريس أطفالهم.
So that was the basis of it,
إذاً كان ذلك أساس الأمر
was one-on-one attention.
كان إنتباه شخص لشخص.
And we found ourselves full every day with kids.
ووجدنا أنفسنا مشغولين بشدة كل يوم مع الاطفال.
If you're on Valencia Street within those few blocks at around 2 p.m.,
إذا كنت في شارع فالنسيا مع تلك المربوعات القليلة حوالي الساعة 2:00،
2:30 p.m., you will get run over, often,
2:30، سيتم دهسك ، عادة،
by the kids and their big backpacks, or whatever, actually running to this space,
بواسطة الأطفال أو حقائبهم الكبيرة، أو أي شئ، في الواقع يسرعون لهذه المساحة.
which is very strange, because it's school, in a way.
الذي هو غريب بشدة، لأنها مدرسة، بصورة ما.
But there was something psychological happening there
لكن هناك شئ نفسي يحدث هناك
that was just a little bit different.
كان الأمر مختلف قليلاً
And the other thing was, there was no stigma.
والشئ الآخر أنه لم يكن هناك علامة فارقة للأطفال
Kids weren't going into the "Center-for-Kids-That-Need-More-Help,"
لم يكن الأطفال ذاهبون الى "مركز للأطفال الذين يحتاجون لمزيد من المساعدة"
or something like that. It was 826 Valencia.
أو شئ من هذا القبيل. لقد كانت 826 فالنسيا
First of all, it was a pirate supply store, which is insane.
بادئ ذي بدء، لقد كان متجر مستلزمات قرصنة، الذي هو جنوني.
And then secondly, there's a publishing company in the back.
وثانياً، كانت هناك شركة طباعة في الخلف.
And so our interns were actually working
ولذا كان متدربينا يعملون في الواقع
at the same tables very often,
على نفس الطاولات بصورة دائمة،
and shoulder-to-shoulder, computer-next-to-computer with the students.
وكتف لكتف، كمبيوتر بجانب كمبيوتر مع التلاميذ.
And so it became a tutoring center --
ولذا أصبح مركز تدريس --
publishing center, is what we called it --
سميناه مركز نشر
and a writing center.
ومركز للكتابة.
They go in, and they might be working with a high school student
يدخلون وربما يعملون مع طلاب ثانوية عليا
actually working on a novel -- because we had very gifted kids, too.
في الواقع يعملون على رواية -- لأن لدينا بعض الأطفال الموهوبين جداً
So there's no stigma.
لا توجد علامة فارقة
They're all working next to each other. It's all a creative endeavor.
أنهم يعملون جميعاً بجانب بعضهم البعض. ;كلها مساعي إبداعية.
They're seeing adults. They're modeling their behavior.
أنهم يشاهدون الكبار. أنهم يجسدون سلوكهم.
These adults, they're working in their field.
هؤلاء الكبار، يعملون في مجالاتهم.
They can lean over, ask a question of one of these adults
يمكنهم التعلم، يسألون أي من أؤلئك الكبار
and it all sort of feeds on each other.
ثم أنها تنتشر بينهم
There's a lot of cross-pollination. The only problem,
هناك الكثير من التلاقح. المشكلة الوحيدة،
especially for the adults working at McSweeney's
خصوصاً للكبار الذين يعملون في ماك سويني
who hadn't necessarily bought into all of this when they signed up,
الذين لم يشاركوا بالضرورة في كل هذا عندما جاءوا،
was that there was just the one bathroom. (Laughter)
كانت هي أن هناك حمام واحد فقط.
With like 60 kids a day, this is a problem.
مع حوالي 60 طفلاً يومياً، هذه مشكلة.
But you know, there's something about the kids finishing their homework
لكن تعرفون، هناك شئ حول الأطفال عندما ينتهون من واجباتهم
in a given day, working one-on-one, getting all this attention --
في يوم محدد، يحصلون على كل الإنتباه --
they go home, they're finished. They don't stall.
يذهبون الى بيوتهم، أنتهوا. لا يماطلون،
They don't do their homework in front of the TV.
لا يقومون بواجباتهم أمام التلفاز.
They're allowed to go home at 5:30 p.m., enjoy their family,
مسموح لهم بالذهاب الى البيت في الساعة 5:30، والإستمتاع مع أسرتهم،
enjoy other hobbies, get outside, play.
الإستمتاع بهواياتهم، الخروج واللعب.
And that makes a happy family.
وهذا يجعل الأسرة سعيدة.
A bunch of happy families in a neighborhood is a happy community.
مجموعة من الأسر السعيدة في الحي في مجتمع سعيد.
A bunch of happy communities tied together is a happy city and a happy world.
مجموعة من المجتمعات السعيدة مترابطة معاً هي مدينة سعيدة وعالم سعيد.
So the key to it all is homework! (Laughter) (Applause)
إذاً مفتاح كل ذلك هو الواجب!
There you have it, you know -- one-on-one attention.
هناك ستحصل عليه -- إنتباه شخص لشخص.
So we started off with about 12 volunteers,
إذاً فقد بدأنا بحوالي 12 متطوع،
and then we had about 50,
ثم تحصلنا على حوالي 50.
and then a couple hundred.
ثم عدة مئات.
And we now have 1,400 volunteers on our roster.
والآن لدينا 1400 متطوع على جدول أعمالنا.
And we make it incredibly easy to volunteer.
ونجعل الامر سهل بشدة للمتطوع.
The key thing is, even if you only have a couple of hours a month,
الشئ المهم انه حتى لو كان لديك ساعات محدودة كل شهر
those two hours shoulder-to-shoulder,
تلك الساعتين كتف لكتف
next to one student, concentrated attention,
بجانب تلميذ واحد، إنتباه مركّز
shining this beam of light on their work,
شعاع ساطع من الضوء على أعمالهم
on their thoughts and their self-expression,
على أفكارهم وتعبيرهم عن أنفسهم
is going to be absolutely transformative,
ستكون نقطة تحول مطلقة
because so many of the students have not had that ever before.
لأن العديد من الطلاب لم تتح لهم هذه الفرصة من قبل
So we said, "Even if you have two hours one Sunday every six months,
لذا فقد قلنا، " حتى إذا كان لديك ساعتين يوم الاحد كل 6 أشهر،
it doesn't matter. That's going to be enough."
فالأمر لا يهم. سيكون هذا كافياً
So that's partly why the tutor corps grew so fast.
كان ذلك سبب نمو جوهر التدريس بسرعة
Then we said, "Well, what are we
ثم قلنا حسناً
going to do with the space during the day,
ماذا سنقوم بفعله بالمساحة خلال اليوم
because it has to be used before 2:30 p.m.?"
لأنه يجب إستخدامه قبل الساعة 2:30؟
So we started bringing in classes during the day.
لذا فقد بدأنا بالتجمع في الفصول خلال اليوم
So every day, there's a field trip where they together create a book --
إذاً كل يوم هناك رحلة ميدانية حيث يتجمعون لصنع كتاب
you can see it being typed up above.
يمكنكم رؤيته يطبع هناك في الأعلى
This is one of the classes getting way too excited about writing.
هذا أحد الفصول يصبح أكثر إثارة حول الكتابة
You just point a camera at a class,
عندما توجّه الكاميرا نحو أي فصل
and it always looks like this.
دائماً يبدو هكذا
So this is one of the books that they do.
إذاً هذا أحد الكتب التي يقومون بها
Notice the title of the book,
إنتبهوا لعنوان الكتاب
"The Book That Was Never Checked Out: Titanic."
" الكتاب الذي لم يتم إستعارته أبداً: تايتانيك
And the first line of that book is, "Once there was a book named Cindy
وأول سطر في ذلك الكتاب هو بمجرد وجود كتاب يسمى كيندي
that was about the Titanic."
فانه حول تايتانيك
So, meanwhile, there's an adult in the back typing this up,
إذاً في هذه الأثناء هناك شخص في الخلف يطبع هذا
taking it completely seriously, which blows their mind.
يأخذ الامر على محمل الجد الذي يفجّر طاقات عقولهم
So then we still had more tutors to use.
إذاً فما يزال لدينا مدرسين أكثر لنستخدمهم
This is a shot of just some of the tutors during one of the events.
هذه لقطة لبعض المدرسين خلال أحد المناسبات
The teachers that we work with --
المعلمين الذين نعمل معهم
and everything is different to teachers -- they tell us what to do.
وكل شئ مختلف بالنسبة للمعلمين يخبروننا ماذا نفعل
We went in there thinking,
بدأنا بالتفكير
"We're ultimately, completely malleable. You're going to tell us.
نحن أساساً مرنين للغاية, ستقومون بإخبارنا
The neighborhood's going to tell us, the parents are going to tell us.
الآباء سيقوموا بإخبارنا
The teachers are going to tell us how we're most useful."
سيقوم المعلمون بإخبارنا كم نحن مفيدين
So then they said, "Why don't you come into the schools?
ثم عندها قالوا،" لماذا لا تأتون الى المدرسة؟
Because what about the students that wouldn't come to you,
ماذا عن التلاميذ الذين لا يأتون إليكم
necessarily, who don't have really active parents that are bringing them in,
هم تحديدا الذين ليس لديهم آباء نشيطين لجلبهم
or aren't close enough?" So then we started saying,
أو ليسوا مقربين بما يكفي؟ عندها بدأنا بالقول
"Well, we've got 1,400 people on our tutor roster.
حسناً لدينا 1400 شخص على جدول أعمال التدريس
Let's just put out the word." A teacher will say,
فلنعلن أن المدرس سيقول:
"I need 12 tutors for the next five Sundays.
أحتاج ل 12 معلماً للخمسة أسابيع القادمة
We're working on our college essays. Send them in."
نحن نعمل على مقالات في الكلية "أرسلهم لنا"
So we put that out on the wire: 1,400 tutors.
إذاً فقد وضعنا كل ذلك في الحسبان 1400 معلم
Whoever can make it signs up. They go in about a half an hour before the class.
كل من يستطيع المشاركة يشارك بحوالي ساعة ونصف قبل موعد الدرس
The teacher tells them what to do,
يخبرهم المعلمون بما ينبغي عليهم فعله
how to do it, what their training is, what their project is so far.
كيف يقومون به، ما هو تدريبهم وما هو مشروعهم حتى الآن
They work under the teacher's guide,
يعملون تحت إشراف المعلم
and it's all in one big room.
وكل هذا في قاعة واحدة كبيرة
And that's actually the brunt of what we do is,
وهذا في الواقع ما أردنا أن نقوم به
people going straight from their workplace, straight from home,
الناس يذهبون مباشرة من أماكن عملهم أو مباشرة من منازلهم،
straight into the classroom and
مباشرة الى الفصول الدراسية
working directly with the students.
يعملون بشكل مباشر مع التلاميذ
So then we're able to work with thousands and thousands of more students.
إذاً بمقدورنا العمل مع آلالاف وآلالاف التلاميذ
Then another school said, "Well, what if we
ثم قالت مدرسة أخرى حسناً ماذا لو أننا
just give you a classroom and you can staff it all day?"
قدمنا لكم فصول ولكم أن تشغلوها طوال اليوم؟
So this is the Everett Middle School Writers' Room,
إذاً ها هي قاعة مدرسة إيفريت المتوسطة للكتاب،
where we decorated it in buccaneer style.
حيث قمنا بتصميمها بأسلوب القرصان
It's right off the library. And there we serve
انها أمام المكتبة وهناك نقوم
all 529 kids in this middle school.
بخدمة ال 529 طفلاً في هذه المدرسة المتوسطة
This is their newspaper, the "Straight-Up News,"
هذه جريدتهم : أخبار سترايت أب
that has an ongoing column from Mayor Gavin Newsom
ولها عمود دائم من عمدة جافين نيوسوم
in both languages -- English and Spanish.
باللغتين الإنجليزية والأسبانية
So then one day Isabel Allende wrote to us and said,
ثم في أحد الأيام كتبت لنا إيزابيل الاندي وقالت
"Hey, why don't you assign a book with high school students?
هاى، لم لا تعينوا كتاباً لطلاب الثانوية العليا؟
I want them to write about how to achieve peace in a violent world."
أريدهم أن يكتبوا حول كيفية تحقيق السلام في مناطق العنف في العالم
And so we went into Thurgood Marshall High School,
ولذا ذهبنا لمدرسة ثورقوود مارشال الثانوية
which is a school that we had worked with on some other things,
التي عملنا معها على بعض الأشياء الأخرى
and we gave that assignment to the students.
وقمنا بتعيين ذلك الواجب للطلاب
And we said, "Isabel Allende is going to read all your essays at the end.
وقلنا، " ستقرأ إيزابيل ألاندي كل كتاباتكم في النهاية.
She's going to publish them in a book.
وستقوم بنشرها في كتاب
She's going to sponsor the printing of this book in paperback form.
وستقوم بدعم تكاليف طباعة الكتاب على الورق
It's going to be available in all the bookstores in the Bay Area
وسيكون متوفراً في كل المكتبات في منطقة الخليج
and throughout the world, on Amazon and you name it."
وفي كل العالم عبر موقع أمازون وبكل الوسائل
So these kids worked harder
ولذا عمل أؤلئك الأطفال بجدية أكثر
than they've ever worked on anything in their lives,
عن أي وقت مضى طوال حياتهم
because there was that outside audience,
بسبب وجود جمهور خارجي
there was Isabel Allende on the other end.
كانت هناك ايزابيل ألاندي في النهاية
I think we had about 170 tutors that worked on this book with them
أعتقد أنه كان لدينا 170 أستاذ عملوا معهم في هذا الكتاب
and so this worked out incredibly well.
ولذا فقد نجح هذا بطريقة مذهلة
We had a big party at the end.
وكان لدينا حفل كبير في النهاية
This is a book that you can find anywhere. So that led to a series of these.
هذا كتاب يمكنكم الحصول عليه من أي مكان وقاد هذا لسلسلة من الكتب
You can see Amy Tan sponsored the next one,
يمكنك رؤية آمي تان ترعى الكتاب التالي
"I Might Get Somewhere."
" ربما أصل لمكان ما "
And this became an ongoing thing. More and more books.
وأصبح هذا شيئاً مستمراً. المزيد والمزيد من الكتب
Now we're sort of addicted to the book thing.
نحن الآن نوع ما مدمنين على فكرة الكتب هذه
The kids will work harder than they've ever worked in their life
سيعمل الاطفال بجد أكثر من أي وقت مضى في حياتهم
if they know it's going to be permanent,
إذا عرفوا أنه سيكون شيئاً مستمراً
know it's going to be on a shelf,
عرفوا أنه سيكون على الرف
know that nobody can diminish what they've thought and said,
عرفوا أنه لا يمكن لشخص أن يبخس أي شئ فكروا به وقالوه
that we've honored their words, honored their thoughts
أننا قدّرنا كلماتهم، قدّرنا أفكارهم
with hundreds of hours of five drafts, six drafts --
مع مئات الساعات من خمسة مشاريع، ستة مشاريع--
all this attention that we give to their thoughts.
كل هذا الإنتباه الذي نوليه لأفكارهم
And once they achieve that level, once they've written at that level,
وبمجرد تحقيقهم لهذا المستوى، بمجرد أن كتبوا بذاك المستوى
they can never go back.
لن يتراجعوا بتاتاً
It's absolutely transformative.
أنه أمر إنتقالي على الإطلاق
And so then they're all sold in the store. This is near the planks.
وثم بيعت كلها في المكتبات. هذا بالقرب من الألواح
We sell all the student books.
نحن نبيع كل كتب الطلاب.
Where else would you put them, right?
كذلك أين يمكن وضعها، حسناً؟
So we sell 'em, and then something weird had been happening
إذاً نحن نبيعها، ثم شئ غريب كان يحصل
with the stores. The store, actually --
مع المكتبات. المكتبة، في الواقع--
even though we started out as just a gag -- the store actually made money.
رغماً عن اننا بدأناها كمجرد هفوة -- المكتبة في الواقع جنت أموالاً.
So it was paying the rent.
لذا كان المال يغطي الإيجار.
And maybe this is just a San Francisco thing --
وربما هذا الشئ متعلق بسان فرانسيسكو فقط--
I don't know, I don't want to judge.
لا أعرف، لا أريد الحكم.
But people would come in --
لكن يأتي الناس --
and this was before the pirate movies and everything!
وكل هذا قبل أفلام قرصنة وكل شئ!
It was making a lot of money. Not a lot of money,
كانت تدّر الكثير من المال. ليس الكثير،
but it was paying the rent, paying a full-time staff member there.
لكنه يغطي الإيجار، وكذلك تكاليف المعلمين الدائمين هناك
There's the ocean maps you can see on the left.
هناك خارطة للمحيطات يمكنكم رؤيتها على اليسار
And it became a gateway to the community.
وقد أصبحت بوابة للمجتمع
People would come in and say, "What the --?
يأتي الناس ويقولوا، "ما هو...؟
What is this?" I don't want to swear on the web. (Laughter)
ما هذا؟ لا أريد القسم على الشبكة
Is that a rule? I don't know.
هل هذه قاعدة؟ لا أعرف
They would say, "What is this?"
يقولون، " ما هذا؟"
And people would come in and learn more about it.
ويأتي الناس ويتعلمون أكثر عنها
And then right beyond -- there's usually a little chain there --
ثم خلفها تماماً-- هناك في العادة سلسلة صغيرة هناك--
right beyond, they would see the kids being tutored.
بالخلف مباشرة، بإمكانهم رؤية الأطفال يتم تدريسهم
This is a field trip going on. And so they would be shopping,
هذه رحلة ميدانية جارية. ولهذا يكونوا في تسوقهم،
and they might be more likely to buy some lard,
وربما من المرجح أنهم يريدون شراء بعض شحم الخنزير،
or millet for their parrot, or, you know, a hook,
أو دخن للببغاء، أو تعلمون، خطاف،
or hook protector for nighttime, all of these things we sell.
أو حامي الخطاف للأوقات الليلية، نبيع كل هذه الأشياء
So the store actually did really well.
عمل المتجر بصورة جيدة في الواقع
But it brought in so many people --
لكنه جلب الكثير من الناس
teachers, donors, volunteers, everybody --
المعلمون، المتبرعون، المتطوعون، كل شخص
because it was street level. It was open to the public.
لأنه كان على مستوى الشارع. كان متاحا للعامة
It wasn't a non-profit buried, you know, on the 30th floor
لم يكن ربحية مدفونة، تعلمون، في الطابق الثلاثين
of some building downtown. It was right in the neighborhood
أو مبنى ما في وسط المدينة. كان في وسط الحي الذي كان يخدمه
that it was serving, and it was open all the time to the public.
كان مفتوحاً طوال الوقت للجمهور.
So, it became this sort of weird, happy accident.
لذا، أصبح نوعاً ما غريباً، صدفة سعيدة
So all the people I used to know in Brooklyn, they said,
إذاً كل الناس الذين عرفتهم في بروكلين، قالوا
"Well, why don't we have a place like that here?"
"حسناً، لم لا نحصل على مكان كهذا هنا؟"
And a lot of them had been former educators
وكان الكثيرين منهم معلمين سابقين
or would-be educators, so they combined
أو سيكونوا معلمين، لذا فقد إجتمعوا
with a lot of local designers, local writers,
مع الكثير من المصممين المحليين، الكُتّاب المحليين
and they just took the idea independently
وأخذوا الفكرة بصورة مستقلة
and they did their own thing.
وقاموا بتنفيذها على طريقتهم
They didn't want to sell pirate supplies.
لم يرغبوا في بيع مستلزمات قرصنة
They didn't think that that was going to work there.
لم يعتقدوا أن الأمر سينجح هناك
So, knowing the crime-fighting community in New York,
لذا، بمعرفة مجتمع مكافحة الجريمة في مدينة نيويورك
they opened the Brooklyn Superhero Supply Company.
أفتتحوا شركة بروكلين لتزويد الأبطال الخارقين
This is Sam Potts' great design that did this.
وهذا تصميم سام بوتس العظيم الذي أنجز هذا
And this was to make it look sort of like one of those
وكان هذا لجعلها تبدو كواحدة من هذه
keysmith's shops that has to have every service
متاجر كي سميث التي لديها كل الخدمات
they've ever offered, you know, all over there.
يمكنهم تقديمها، تعلمون، كل شئ هناك
So they opened this place. Inside, it's like a Costco
إذاً فقد أفتتحوا هذا المكان, من داخل شبيه بكوستاكو
for superheroes -- all the supplies in kind of basic form.
للأبطال الخارقين-- كل هذه المستلزمات على شكل إحتياجات أساسية.
These are all handmade.
هذه مصنوعة يدوياً.
These are all sort of repurposed other products, or whatever.
هذه أنواع من إعادة إستخدام لمنتجات أخرى
All the packaging is done by Sam Potts.
كل التعبئة أنجزها سام بوتس
So then you have the villain containment unit,
ثم تحصل على وحدة إحتواء الأشرار
where kids put their parents. You have the office.
حيث يضع الأطفال آبائهم. يوجد المكتب.
This is a little vault -- you have to put your product in there,
هذا قبو صغير-- تضع منتجك هناك
it goes up an electric lift
يذهب لأعلى بالرافع الكهربائي
and then the guy behind the counter tells you
ثم يقوم الشخص خلف العداد يخبرك
that you have to recite the vow of heroism,
أنه ينبغي عليك قراءة قسم البطولة
which you do, if you want to buy anything. And it limits, really, their sales.
الذي تفعله إذا كنت تريد شراء أي شئ وهذا يقلل من مبيعاتهم في الحقيقة
Personally, I think it's a problem.
شخصياً، أعتقد أنها مشكلة
Because they have to do it hand on heart and everything.
لأنه ينبغي عليهم فعلها بأمانة وصدق
These are some of the products. These are all handmade.
هذه بعض المنتجات, مصنوعة يدوياً
This is a secret identity kit.
هذه علبة هوية سرية
If you want to take on the identity of Sharon Boone,
إذا أردت أن تتقمص شخصية شارون بوني
one American female marketing executive
المديرة التنفيذية أحدى النساء الامريكيات
from Hoboken, New Jersey. It's a full dossier
من هوبوكين، نيو جيرسي. أنها ملف كامل
on everything you would need to know about Sharon Boone.
حول كل شئ ستحتاجه لمعرفة المزيد حول شارون بوني
So, this is the capery where you get fitted for your cape,
وهذا حيث يمكن ان يتم تفصليها على رأسك
and then you walk up these three steel-graded steps
ثم تصعد ثلاثة درجات مصنوعة من الستييل
and then we turn on three hydraulic fans
ثم ندير ثلاثة مراوح هيدروليكية
from every side and then you can see the cape in action.
من كل جانب وبعدها يمكنك رؤية الرداء
There's nothing worse than, you know,
لا يوجد شئ أسوأ من هذا، تعلمون،
getting up there and the cape is bunching up or something like that.
بالوصول لهذه النقطة وينتفخ الرداء أو شئ من هذا القبيل.
So then, the secret door --
ثم بعد ذلك، الباب السري --
this is one of the shelves you don't see
هذه أحد الأرفف التي لا ترونها
when you walk in, but it slowly opens.
لاحظوا عندما تمشي تجاهها تفتح ببطء.
You can see it there in the middle next to all the grappling hooks.
يمكنكم رؤيتها هنا في الوسط بجانب الخطافات المتماسكة
It opens and then this is the tutoring center in the back. (Applause)
أنه يفتح ثم هذا هو مركز التدريس في الخلفية
So you can see the full effect!
يمكنك رؤيتها بالتأثير الكامل
But this is -- I just want to emphasize --
لكن هذا-- رغبت فقط بالتوضيح--
locally funded, locally built.
ممولة محلياً، مبنية محلياً
All the designers, all of the builders,
كل المصممين، كل البنائين
everybody was local, all the time was pro-bono.
كل شئ كان محلياً، طول الوقت كان يحصل كخدمة اجتماعية
I just came and visited and said, "Yes, you guys are doing great,"
جئت للتو وزرتهم وقلت،" نعم، أنتم تقومون بشئ عظيم،"
or whatever. That was it. You can see the time
هذا ما كان يمكنكم رؤية الوقت
in all five boroughs of New York in the back. (Laughter) (Applause)
في جميع الأقاليم في نيويورك في الخلف
So this is the space during tutoring hours.
إذاً هذا هو المكان خلال ساعات التدريس.
It's very busy. Same principles: one-on-one attention,
إنه مشغول بشدة. بعض المبادئ: إنتباه شخص لشخص اخر
complete devotion to the students' work
تفاني كامل لعمل الطلاب
and a boundless optimism and sort of a possibility
وتفاؤل بلا حدود ونوع من الإمكانات
of creativity and ideas.
للإبداع والأفكار
And this switch is flicked in their heads
وهذا المفتاح تحرك في رؤوسهم
when they walk through those 18 feet of this bizarre store, right?
عندما يسيروا عبر هذا المخزن الغريب بطول ثمانية عشر قدماً، صحيح؟
So it's school, but it's not school.
إذاً إنها مدرسة، لكنها ليست مدرسة
It's clearly not school, even though
من الواضح انها ليست مدرسة، رغماً عن هذا
they're working shoulder-to-shoulder on tables, pencils and papers, whatever.
أنهم يعملون كتفا بكتف على الطاولات، الأقلام والأوراق، وكل شئ
This is one of the students, Khaled Hamdan.
هذا أحد الطلاب، خالد حمدان
You can read this quote.
يمكنكم قراءة هذا الإقتباس
Addicted to video games and TV. Couldn't concentrate at home.
مدمن على ألعاب الفيديو والتلفاز. لم أستطيع التركيز في البيت
Came in. Got this concentrated attention.
جئت هنا. حصلت على هذا الإنتباه المركز
And he couldn't escape it.
ولم يستطيع الهروب منه
So, soon enough, he was writing. He would finish his homework early --
وبفترة وجيزة كان يكتب أنه ينتهي من واجباته مبكراً
got really addicted to finishing his homework early.
أصبح مدمناً على الإنتهاء من واجباته
It's an addictive thing to sort of be done with it,
إنها إدمان على نوع من الإنتهاء منها
and to have it checked, and to know he's going to achieve
ويتم تصحيحها وأنه سيقوم بتحقيق
the next thing and be prepared for school the next day.
الشئ القادم ويجهز للمدرسة في اليوم التالي
So he got hooked on that, and then he started doing other things.
لذا فقد أصبح متعلقاً بذلك، ثم بدأ في فعل أشياء أخرى
He's now been published in five books.
وتم نشر كتابات له في خمسة كتب حتى الان
He co-wrote a mockumentary about failed superheroes
وهو يكتب بجانب موكومنتري حول أبطال خارقين فاشلين
called "Super-Has-Beens."
يسمى "كانوا سوبر"
He wrote a series on "Penguin Balboa,"
لقد كتب سلسلة حول "البطريق بلبوة"
which is a fighting -- a boxing -- penguin.
الذي هو بطريق مقاتل -ملاكم-.
And then he read aloud just a few weeks ago to 500 people at Symphony Space,
وقد قرأ بصوت عالي قبل حوالي أسابيع قليلة مضت أمام 500 شخص في مركز للفنون
at a benefit for 826 New York. So he's there every day.
من أجل فائدة 826 نيويورك. لذا فهوهناك كل يوم
He's evangelical about it. He brings his cousins in now.
أنه مأسور بها. وهو يجلب أبناء عمومته الآن
There's four family members that come in every day.
هناك أربع أفراد من الأسرة يأتون كل يوم.
So, I'll go through really quickly.
إذا، سأمر بسرعة على هذا
This is L.A., The Echo Park Time Travel Mart:
هذه لوس أنجلوس، سوق حديقة صدى سفر الوقت
"Whenever You Are, We're Already Then." (Laughter)
"وقتما كنت، فنحن بالفعل هناك."
This is sort of a 7-Eleven for time travelers.
هذا نوع من متجر 7-11 للمسافرين عبر الزمن
So you see everything: it's exactly as a 7-Eleven would be.
إذا ترون كل شئ: أنه بالضبط مثلما سيكون عليه 7-11
Leeches. Mammoth chunks. They even have their own Slurpee machine:
العلق. قطع الماموث. حتى أن لديهم ماكينتهم الخاصة للتبول:
"Out of Order. Come Back Yesterday." (Laughter) (Applause)
" خارج الخدمة. تعال بالأمس."
Anyway. So I'm going to jump ahead.
على كل حال. سأقوم بالمضي قدماً.
These are spaces that are only affiliated with us,
هذه أماكن فقط مرتبطة بنا
doing this same thing: Word St. in Pittsfield, Massachusetts;
نفعل نفس الشئ: وورد سانت، في بيتسفيلد، ماساتشوستس
Ink Spot in Cincinnati; Youth Speaks, San Francisco, California,
بقعة حبر في سينسيناتي. يوث سبيكس، سان فرانسيسكو، كاليفورينا،
which inspired us; Studio St. Louis in St. Louis;
التي ألهمتنا. ستديو في سانت لويس في سانت لويس.
Austin Bat Cave in Austin;
كهف في مدينة أوستن.
Fighting Words in Dublin, Ireland, started by Roddy Doyle,
كلمات مقاتلة في دبلن، إيرلندا، بدأها رودي ديولي
this will be open in April.
هذا سيفتتح في أبريل
Now I'm going to the TED Wish -- is that okay?
الآن أنا بصدد أمنية تيد-- هل هذا جيد؟
All right, I've got a minute. So, the TED Wish:
حسناً، لدي دقيقة لأمنية تيد:
I wish that you -- you personally and every creative individual
أتمنى أن -- أنتم شخصياً وكل شخص مبدع
and organization you know -- will find a way
ومؤسسة كما تعلمون -- أن تجدوا طريقة
to directly engage with a public school in your area
للتعامل المباشر مع المدارس العامة في منطقتكم
and that you'll then tell the story of how you got involved,
ثم تخبرونهم قصة كيف أننا شاركنا
so that within a year we have a thousand examples --
بحيث أنه خلال سنة نحصل على آلف مثال--
a thousand! -- of transformative partnerships.
ألف! -- من الشراكات التحويلية
Profound leaps forward!
قفزات عميقة الى الأمام!
And these can be things that maybe you're already doing.
وهذه قد تكون أشياء ربما تفعلونها بالفعل
I know that so many people in this room
أعرف أن الكثير من الناس في هذه القاعة
are already doing really interesting things.
بالفعل يفعلون أشياء مثيرة حقاً
I know that for a fact. So, tell us these stories and inspire others on the website.
أعرف هذا كحقيقة. لذا، أخبرونا هذه القصص وألهموا الآخرين على صفحة الإنترنت
We created a website.
لقد أسسنا موقع على الإنترنت
I'm going to switch to "we," and not "I," hope:
سأقوم بالإنتقال من "أنا" إلى "نحن نتمنى"
We hope that the attendees of this conference will usher in
نأمل أن هذا الحضور في هذا المؤتمر سيكونوا فاتحة
a new era of participation in our public schools.
لحقبة جديدة من المشاركة في المدارس العامة.
We hope that you will take the lead
نأمل أن تأخذوا زمام المبادرة
in partnering your innovative spirit and expertise
في رعاية روح الإبتكار والخبرة
with that of innovative educators in your community.
مع أؤلئك المعلمين المبدعين في مجتمعكم المحلي
Always let the teachers lead the way.
دائماً أجعلوا المدرسين يقودون الطريق.
They will tell you how to be useful. I hope that you'll step in and help out.
سيخبرونكم كيف تكونوا نافعين. أملي أنكم ستتقدمون وتساعدوا
There are a million ways.
هناك ملايين الطرق
You can walk up to your local school
يمكنك الذهاب الى المدرسة المحلية
and consult with the teachers. They'll always tell you how to help.
وتتشاوروا مع المعلمين. سيخبرونكم دائماً بكيفية المساعدة.
So, this is with Hot Studio in San Francisco,
إذا-- هذا مع الأستديو النشط في سان فرانسيسكو
they did this phenomenal job.
لقد قاموا بهذا العمل الخارق.
This website is already up, it's already got a bunch of stories,
حصل هذا الموقع بالفعل على بضع قصص
a lot of ideas. It's called "Once Upon a School,"
الكثير من الأفكار. تسمى بناء مدرسة واحدة،"
which is a great title, I think.
الذي هو أسم عظيم، أعتقد
This site will document every story, every project that comes
سيقوم الموقع بتوثيق كل مشروع يأتي
out of this conference and around the world. So you go to the website,
من هذا المؤتمر وحول العالم. لذا اذهبوا الى الموقع
you see a bunch of ideas you can be inspired by
يمكنكم رؤية العديد من الأفكار. يمكنها أن تلهمكم
and then you add your own projects once you get started.
ثم تضيف مشروعك الخاص بمجرد أن تبدأه
Hot Studio did a great job in a very tight deadline. So, visit the site.
الأستديو الساخن أنجز عملاً عظيماً في وقت قصير للغاية، لذا زوروا الموقع
If you have any questions, you can ask this guy,
إذا كان لديكم أي سؤال، يمكنك سؤال هذا الشخص
who's our director of national programs. He'll be on the phone.
الذي هو مدير برامجنا القومية. سيكون على الهاتف
You email him, he'll answer any question you possibly want.
يمكنك مراسلته بالبريد، سيجيب على أي سؤال يحتمل أن تسألوه
And he'll get you inspired and get you going
وسيقوم بإلهامكم ويساعدكم
and guide you through the process so that you can affect change.
ويرشدكم طوال العملية بحيث يمكنك إحداث التغيير
And it can be fun! That's the point of this talk --
ويمكن أن تكون ممتعة! هذا هو هدف هذا الحديث
it needn't be sterile. It needn't be bureaucratically untenable.
ليس بالضرورة أن تكون عقيمة. لا يستوجب أن تكون بيروقراطية لا يمكن الدفاع عنها.
You can do and use the skills that you have.
يمكنكم فعلها وتوظيف المهارات المتوفرة لديكم
The schools need you. The teachers need you.
المدارس تحتاجكم. المعلمون يحتاجونكم
Students and parents need you. They need your actual person:
الطلاب والآباء يحتاجونكم. يحتاجون للإنسان الكامن فيكم
your physical personhood and your open minds
وجودكم الفيزيائي وعقولكم المفتوحة
and open ears and boundless compassion,
والأذن المفتوحة وتسامحكم اللا محدود
sitting next to them, listening and nodding
تجلسون بقربهم، تستمعون وإيماءتكم
and asking questions for hours at a time.
وتسألون أسئلة لساعات من الزمن
Some of these kids just don't plain know how good they are:
بعض أؤلئك الأطفال فقط لا يعرفون كم هم جيدين
how smart and how much they have to say.
كم هم أذكياء وكم لديهم ليقولوه.
You can tell them. You can shine that light on them,
يمكنكم أخبارهم. يمكنكم إضاءة ذلك الضوء لهم
one human interaction at a time. So we hope you'll join us.
تفاعل إنساني واحد كل مرة. لذا نأمل أن تنضموا إلينا
Thank you so much.
شكراً جزيلاً لكم.